Now that it appears our car is moving forward, we can now look to creating the mechanics for our car.
Basically what we want to happen is we want to be able to move our car across the road with our arrow
keys.
Now, do I even need to explain how to do this?
Because I am sure by now you know how to get this code right, as we have built the same mechanics in
our previous games.
So if you want to, you can try do this for yourself.
Otherwise I'm going to run through this quickly.
So if you're keen, pause the video and see if you can figure this part out for yourself.
Well, you know the drill.
We need a forever.
We need two if then blocks.
We need two of these key pressed sensing blocks in each of our if statements.
Then we can change the first one to the left arrow.
And the second to the right arrow.
We can then go into our motion box, grab the change X by and add one to each of these.
Then for the right we will change x by a positive ten as it is, and for the left it will be a negative
ten.
So clicking the play now.
There you go.
A car is controllable and a game is starting to take shape.
One thing, however, is you can see the road is on top of our car, so it's just going to the road.
Sprite.
We can move to looks and we can bring in this block here which says go to and we can change the back
layer.
And this is another important thing to know about.
Like when we look at our screen here it looks like just a flat image.
But there are actually multiple layers in each sprite can be a different layer.
You see, layers help us create depth in our projects, making them more visually appealing.
And we will be using layers in this project to think of layers, sort of like a stack of papers or a
sandwich.
In scratch, each sprite exists on its own layer.
When you add new sprite, they are placed on top of existing ones, and this determines the order in
which they appear on the screen.
But you can change the order of these layers.
This allows you to easily arrange your sprites so that some appear on top of others, creating depth
and a more polished look for your project.
You'll get the idea better as we move forward, but for now, notice how much better this is.